Dina Eissa

Frontend Developer/Web Designer

San Francisco Bay Area, CA | +1 (415) 9419819

- @ dinamshawky@gmail.com
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/dinameissa
- https://github.com/Dina-Eissa

SUMMARY

A talented web designer and frontend developer with more than five years of experience seeking a position where my talent and understanding of technology background can be best utilized. I am team player, self-driven and always motivated to learn new technologies, I am a fast learner and striving to deliver efficiently and effectively.

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, OOP, Javascript, JQuery, SQL, API, Node.js, Express.js, handlebars.js, MVC, Git.

Multimedia Applications: Adobe Photoshop. Responsive Framework: Bootstrap, Bulma.

EXPERIENCE

Frontend developer

Click ITS (Freelance) Jan 2020 to now

- Involved in developing the UI pages using HTML, CSS, Javascript, JSON and Jquery.
- Developed front for the entire website using HTML5, CSS3, and Javascript.
- Applied jquery core library functions for the logical implementation of all the applications at the client side.
- Testing the website on multiple browsers with their old as well as latest release.
- Created SQL queries to perform insert, update or delete operation on MySQL database.
- Developed application for different browsers and fixed bugs for browser compatibility.

Web Designer

Click ITS (Full time) Jan 2013 to Sept 2017

- Created the visual layout of web pages to achieve design goals using photoshop.
- Performed front-end development for interactive web applications to improve functionality and user experience using HTML, CSS, and JQuery.
- Created responsive websites and web applications using Bootstrap.
- Proposed and implemented new site content architecture and navigation scheme for company website redesign.
- Ensured accuracy of website content by thoroughly editing and cross-checking.
- Build websites using WordPress.
- Customize themes to meet clients' requirements.

EDUCATION

University of California, Berkeley in USA

Coding Boot Camp, Computer Science – Mar 2022 – Nov 2022

Arab Academy for Science, Technology and Maritime Transport - Faculty of Computer Science in Egypt

■ Information Systems Pre-Masters - 2016 - GPA (3.8).

Ain Shams University - Faculty of Computer and Information Science in Cairo, Egypt

■ Information Technology Post-Graduate "Higher Diploma" – 2013 – Grade (Excellent).

Ain Shams University - Faculty of Commerce in Cairo, Egypt

Bachelor's Degree.